Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
[music]
Look at you, beauty. He catch you with another man.
This wasn't the first time you disappointed your father, was it?
How old were you when you had your first child? [music]
[music]
I don't know who Sammy's father is.
Is that because you've had so many sexual partners?
No way. Josie, the mind's hiring. You know, you drive truck drunk.
Yours truly. First woman ever. Would you like to make the same kind of money your dad does?
She's not going to be living with her, folks. All clear. Clear of what?
You're not pregnant. You submitted to the exam willingly, correct? Before your law firm hired you, they put your feet in the air, look around your insides,
and if you take a job up there, what a little shame it.
You know, they don't want us up there. Yeah, I got that.
And all sorts of other things a woman shouldn't be doing, if you ask me. That Supreme Court didn't ask me, did they?
The doc says you look darn good under those clothes.
[music]
All I'm saying is that you can whip it out anytime, Hank. We got to pull the coveralls all the way down. You know what I'm saying?
Should look in that first. You never know in this place. Come on. We'll see what the girls.
No getting off the lunchroom, ladies.
There's nothing else. It's a move to adjourn. Porter Johnson. Here we go again.
It's a Hamilton 60 years old.
Think you're one of my girls, right? If you have any problems, you make sure you come and see me.
I'm a cigarette then a kid of myself.
You're taking jobs where there aren't any to take. Work hard. Keep your mouth shut.
You're like little boys love, don't you?
You got to get a gator skin on. You're going to work in this stink hole. I just don't want him to have any reason to get rid of his all.
I don't know how I'm ever going to thank you. First time in my life I'm making my own money. I just feel like for the first time in my life like I'm
[singing]
[music]
even ladies. [laughter]
Holy crap. Okay.
Conveyor's down. So, I need someone to get up there and see if something's clogging the works. Go on.
What's the matter with you? Well, it was pretty typical behavior. You want to know the truth? Josie made a lot of mountains from mole hills.
You don't got to be scared that one of these days you'll come to work and get right.
Josie, I I don't think you and Bill have met. Have you tell me he's not over?
My family would killed me in photos talked to you. You Josie James. Yeah.
Damn mining [ __ ] You just keep away from Bobby. You know what's good for you.
Sammy says to tell you that he's going to stay at my house tonight. You're a [ __ ] Just like everyone said.
Talk to me like that. [music]
It's me. Glory can't make it. She's got a bad flu. Oh no. I need her here. I told you, Josie. She's sick. Well, can I talk to her?
Josie, she's not coming. All right, where are you going?
Guys, what I was saying before was I think we should go to Pearson. You know, tell them what's going on. What do you get out of this?
Jeez, Peg, I'm just trying to make things better. I mean, hell, it's happening to all of us.
Tell you one thing, getting sick and tired of having my ass grabbed by a bunch of old men.
Maybe you've been asking for it. You ever think of that? Up yours, pig.
Hey, you could quit tomorrow. Go sell your face cream. I need my job.
You don't know [ __ ] about me. I need this job just as much as you.
Okay. Okay. Now, what would you even say to Pearson? We've been sexually harassed. Honey, he'd laugh you out of his office.
Not to mention what the guys would do to us. All that never rat and brother crap.
Yeah. Union old says, "Respect fellow members." Where's that respect?
Sherry. Sherry. Quite good. Cherry. Kiss my ass. It's really hairy. A real funny guy.
Cherry. Hey, cut it out. Just stop it. Cut it out.
What the hell's going on? Show you the crap.
[music]
Miss Ames, sorry to keep you waiting so long. Please sit. Gentlemen, I asked some of my colleagues to sit in, if you don't mind.
No, I believe you know Mr. Pavage.
Yes, I do. Mr. Pavage was the one who told me I had to take a day off work to come and see you. I didn't want to forget anything, so I wrote a couple of
things down on a piece of paper right here.
I already know what you're going to tell me. I've been well briefed.
Um, I think you'll be pleasantly surprised. We've decided to wave the twoe requirement and allow you to tender your resignation effective immediately.
No, I'm sorry. I'm not resigning.
Mr. Cavage will take care of the details. I'd be happy to. No, I need this job.
Well, then I suggest you spend less time stirring up your female co-workers and less time in the beds of your married
male co-workers and more time trying to find ways to improve your job performance.
Sammy, can I come in? It's only 20 minutes late. old freak.
You know, I'm still the mom here. You can't write. What's that supposed to mean?
Nothing. Just most people's mothers cook and clean. Don't work at the mine.
Do you remember when you used to tell me you want to be a doctor when you grew up?
So, so used to tell you could be anything you want. Isn't it the same for me? Aren't I allowed to be anything I
want? Not when you're doing someone else's job. You know, Bill White's going to sign some autographs down at the rink on Saturday. I thought maybe we could go down there.
An autograph from how we lose your boyfriend.
He's not my boyfriend, and he's not a loser. You know, I thought it was something we could go and do together. You love hockey. Quit the team. All right.
When? Who cares?
I care. You love that team. Why didn't you come and talk to me about it?
Cuz I don't want to talk to you. Don't you get it?
[music]
She doesn't have the flu. Josie,
guess he told you, huh?
I never heard of I mean, I've heard of L Garrick. I just never knew about the disease. I know. Kind of like piece by piece.
Your body just quits listening to you like a bullheaded teenager. So, how's Sammy doing?
Hates me. I'd like to say time heals all, but you sure you should be drinking that stuff?
Well, sooner or later, my liver is going to crash and burn on me. So, until then, I'm still in the driver's seat.
You mind if I use your bathroom?
Yeah, go ahead. But come back smiling or I'm going to describe to you what's going to happen to my [ __ ]
I suggest you ladies get some sponges and buckets and get that room clean before somebody gets sick.
They can't do this to us. They're going to keep on doing it worse as long as you keep opening that mouth of yours.
Sherry what they did to you. Wait, he didn't help any. That's for sure. You're a mess. Start cleaning.
Hey Joy, how you like to scratch and sniff wallpaper? Was it him? Was it?
You know what? Give a piece of my check to the union just like everyone else.
You [ __ ] up. What do you want me to say? Hello, Birds. Want to get to work? Should I dim the lights for you?
Joey, get your ass down here. I got a job for you in a pot room. You're one crazy. You know that.
Don't you cra, don't you? Going to learn the goddamn rules. Have to read them any myself.
He attacked me.
Who attacked you? Bobby in the powder room just now.
Bobby, you the hander? The answer's no. I wasn't in the powder room all day.
He was working the concentrator with me all afternoon. See, you call me and Earl Liars now.
Come on. Can somebody drive me home, please?
[snorts]
Where's your dad? He's on nights.
Just take my keys in my locker. Betty, don't. Where do you think you're going?
I quit. The rules are clear. You go around the union, you broke your old period at the end. Glory, what's you doing here?
Does it look like I'm doing? I'm here for the meeting. You're not uh an employer anymore. You're not required to be here.
I mean, I'm not saying Josie should have got into management or anything. We were all sorry to hear you sick.
be an autographed hockey puck.
I want to sue the mine, the company, all of them. I'm saying I want to hire you. Sorry. Don't do that anymore.
Tell you what, I will buy you a beer, though. I don't need a beer. I need a lawyer.
You think you're all gunned at the mine.
Wait till you get to a courtroom. It's called the nuts and [ __ ] defense.
You're either nuts and you imagine it or you're a [ __ ] and you ask for it. Either way, it's not pleasant.
Look, you're a beautiful girl. You could always You're a beautiful girl. I could find a guy to take care of me.
I'm done looking to be taken care of. I want to take care of myself, take care of my kids.
If somebody like her came to see me back in New York with this dog [ __ ] case, you know what I'd do? I'd take it. Settle quick, bucket the contingency, make more money than her, never see a courtroom.
It' be her word against everybody else.
All the guys up there can't be bad, which makes some of them witnesses.
That mine is bread and butter for people around here. Can you get the other women?
You know what a class action is? It's when a bunch of plaintiffs have the same issue. It's tough for the company to
argue that you're all lying. You're all crazy. It's why you have to get the others. Why did I change your mind?
It's never been done before. Sexual harassment, class action. Sue them? Are you kidding?
You know what's going on up there. Life is too short. Trust me.
This is all with the foot on the throat of every woman in that mine. So it's not just my client who needs relief from
this court, your honor. We are asking for an injunction to protect all the women. Further, we ask the court to certify a class, a class made up of
every woman working at Pearson because every one of them deserves protection under the law.
This complaint was filed on behalf of one Josie Ames. The key word there being one. By comparison, we have affidavit from 13 women, all stating there have been no incidents of abuse at Pearson.
It's not true. It's not true. Could be three plaintiffs.
Your honor, please, counselor, if those affidavit are legitimate. You shouldn't have an objection. I'll continue to hear evidence on Ames v. Pearson at all. If
you find three plaintiffs with similar grievances, I'll give you your class action.
Push the button. Push the button. There you go.
My name is Leslie Conlin. I'm an attorney. I represent Pearson Tachinite and Steel. We know who you are.
The other women have signed these affidavit on behalf of the mine. I brought one for you to look at.
Get the hell out of here. You should be ashamed of yourself.
Keep in mind, as long as you're alive, you can be subpoenaed.
Why,
[ __ ]
You think I don't want to stick it up their asses? Then why don't you do it?
And what if we lost? Who else you got so far? I got my own problems.
If she gets any of the other women, they'll get their class and you'll lose this case.
Leslie, why do you think I hired you? I hired you because you were the smartest woman lawyer I could find. But if you're getting soft, I need to know now.
I'm not soft. This woman is a single welfare mother with two kids out of wedlock, assorted sexual history. We don't know if that's true.
Send him in, please.
Would you share with Miss Conland what you told me today?
Mom, everything all right?
How are you and the kids supposed to eat if you don't have a job? I'm your mother, Josie. I haven't always been the best at it. I know, but I'm here.
You give away my hard-earned money and you toss your shoulders at me. I didn't give it away. Gave it to Josie. I work hard for that money, Alice.
Oh, you saying Josie asked for it?
They don't belong in that mine. They never did. You know it. All I know is that girls are daughter.
Our daughters brought nothing but shame on this family. And I said goddamn sick of her.
She had a baby, Henry. She didn't rob a bank.
Alice, is Hank with you? No.
I need a room though. [music] You know what? I'm supposed to get in my
pants. [laughter] I never did anything to this.
That's right. No, she wants to sue all of us. You know what a class action is, don't you?
It means it's all of them against all of us.
I just hope nobody's seeing a break in the ranks back there. Okay, that's it. Let's go.
Comments. Now, before we take the old, are there any other brothers who want to turn it to Gavl? Yeah, I'd like to turn it to Gavl.
Oh my. Oh, she's really lost it. Ask if any brothers would like to speak.
By last day, no meeting can adjourn if a member wants to speak his or her mind. I got your gamble right here.
I'm still a member of this union. Wait, my name is Josie.
Josie, show us your dicks.
Don't look at me, Hank. I'm not the one can't control his family.
Listen. No. Rules. Rules say she gets to talk. Now, you can have the gavl next to any one of you, but right now she's got it. Take the [ __ ] next. All right. All right. But she's got it.
She's got it. My father never wanted me to work here.
Pretty much stopped talking to me because of it. I know some of you here think I want to shut down the market.
Don't worry, sweetheart. We're not going to let it happen.
I just want to go to work like everyone else. Get paid end of the week, feed my kids, and hell, maybe now and then have
enough left for beer at TG Saturday night. And not a woman in that back row don't know what I'm talking about. Time's up.
We need these jobs. It's not going to stop until we say stop. They're done. Three minute rules.
You heard the man out.
It's not going to stop until we say stop. Three minute rule.
There's no threeminut rule. Please. Come on.
Come on. Let it go. My name is Hank Ames and I've been a ranger all my life. So am I. And
I never been ashamed of it till now. You know, when we take our wives and our daughters to the company barbecue, I don't ever hear [clears throat] anybody
calling them those names like [ __ ] and [ __ ] and worse.
I don't ever see nobody grabbing them by their privates or, you know, drawing pictures of them on the bathroom walls doing unspeakables.
unspeakables.
So, what's changed? She's still my daughter, isn't she?
It's a heck of a thing. Watch one get treated that way. You know, you're all supposed to be my friends,
my brothers. Well, right now, I don't have a friend in this room.
In fact, the only one here that I'm not ashamed of is my daughter.
[applause]
[music]
Well, it's tough stuff getting up in front of all those sunset. [snorts] No.
Tough sticking this [ __ ] out day after day without moaning. The rest of us still got to work here.
Easy. Glad to see you do it. It's easy when you're crazy. She's definitely crazy. You're okay getting on that stand and and saying she's lying, right?
I'm going to do what I got to do. Plus, we all sign those affidavits already, which means we don't have a choice anymore, right?
[crying]
[laughter]
Who is Sammy's father? I don't know who Sammy's father is.
Is that because you've had so many sexual partners?
Objection. Plaintiff's sexual history is irrelevant, your honor. Overruled.
Miss Conland, who is the gentleman entering the courtroom?
Mr. Paul Lavansky, your honor. Miss Ames is high school teacher. Who is Sammy?
My son has got nothing to do with any of this.
Is it true that you and your teacher, Mr. Latavansky, had a sexual relationship at one time? A relationship?
What the hell you've been telling them, Bobby?
Miss Ames, did you not at the age of 16 engage in a sexual relationship with your high school teacher?
Well, Josie, stay a moment, would you?
I'd like to have a word with you later.
What are you doing hanging around a boy like Bobby Sharp? You have so much more going for you than a kid like that'll
ever have. I'd like to think of you as more [music] than that. No, no, it's okay.
[music]
Are there any other witnesses to this alleged rape? [music] Anybody besides Mr. Sharp that can corroborate your testimony?
No. Isn't it true that there was no rape?
that in fact you have a long history of inappropriate sexual relationship.
Your honor, at the very least we're talking statuto rape here. You bring my daughter
[snorts]
I'd rather give you money if that's all right with you. It's just looking at it.
She's lying. You know, she didn't get raped by that teacher. She's just saying that so she'll win her lawsuit. She's a [ __ ] just like everybody says.
I wonder if it's illegal to call your own mother a [ __ ] Sure sounds bad enough to be.
She's a liar. My father didn't die in the army. It's a hard truth to tell, Sammy. That's crap. I got a right.
Yeah, you got a lot of rights. Starting with the right to be pissed off. You got a right to hate the whole world right now.
I don't hate the whole world. Just hate her.
Takes a lot of work to hate someone. You ready to put in that kind of time?
To really hate your mom, you got to think over and over again about all the things you hate about her.
She's mean to you, never proud of you, never comes to watch your hockey games, leaves you hungry, never buys you clothes.
Not stupid. Know what you're doing. What's that? I know she does all those things.
Well, you're lucky. She never gave up on you as quick as you'd have given up on her when she was a builder than you are
now. She got pregnant in a way nobody should get pregnant. Would have been a lot easier to give you up to someone else. Nobody would have blamed her if
she did, but she didn't. She stuck by you and she's still sticking by you.
Even though she knows you hate her, she's still there waiting. Take it.
What? Well, if you want to run off, you can sell it and use the money or just put it on your wrist. One friend to another.
Karen, go to bed. I'll wake you when he comes back. Me.
I didn't want you, Sammy. [sighs] Never even occurred to me that there was a baby in there. [snorts]
a day. What that man did to me, it said something about who you were, too. It just kept reminding me of it.
Oh, God. I've dreaded this conversation since the day you were born.
But I don't want any more secrets between us. This one night, I was lying in bed and you moved inside me. I just
knew. I knew you weren't his. You were mine. And we were going to be in it together.
Just the two of us. You had nothing to do with that ugliness. You hear me? Nothing.
And there's nothing in this world I wouldn't do to be your mom. [snorts]
[music]
It's over, isn't it? Not yet.
Mr. Sharp, do you know the difference between consensual sex and rape?
Oh, yeah. But when you're having a good time like she was, no rape, that's for damn sure. Why didn't you help her, Bobby?
Objection.
When you saw Josie being attacked, Miss Ames's testimony has not been corroborated by evidence.
Neither has his, and my client would like to prove that he's lying. I'm allowing it for now. There still was no attack.
I asked around about you, Bobby. Folks say you're kind of soft. Well, anyone that said that ain't meant enough to say it to my face. Are you a red ice player then?
How's that?
I had a coach used to say win or lose, leave your blood on the ice. You're what coach would call a yellow ice player.
Kind that wets his pants when things get rough. Objection. Argumentative. Denied.
She was your friend. You watched him put his filthy hands on her and you ran away.
It wasn't like that, your honor. Stained, Mr. White.
What was it like then? He held her down, spread her legs, jammed himself up inside her.
Mr. White, Rangers are hard as steel. Huh? Not this one. This one's made of butter. You're going to keep lying about your friend.
Are you going to stand up and be a man? Objection. I'm not lying. You want to run right now, don't you? [ __ ] you. All right, that's enough. You want to run, Bobby?
I didn't run.
Or you going to put your guts on the ice this time? What's it going to be? Yellow or red?
Yellow or red? Yellow or red? What was I supposed to do?
He was raping her, wasn't he? Yeah. And he ran.
Was I supposed to?
Well, for starters, you stand up for your friends.
Objection, your honor. You stand up even when you're all alone.
All right. Quite if you are through crossing, what is going on back there?
This is Glory. She worked at Pearson's.
She wants to say, "My name is Glory Dodge, and I'm not [ __ ] dead yet. I stand with Josie.
[music]
Your honor.
Your honor said we needed three plaintiffs. It's still only two.
[music]
Ready?
Hey, your son was just telling me how rich you guys are now. [laughter] Oh, really? You going to buy me a car? No, you're not old enough to drive yet.
So, why are we stopping?
Well, if you want a car someday, you got to know how to drive it, right? Come on.
Oh, okay. [screaming]
[music]
Louis.
foreign
[music]
country.